STEPHEN PEARCE

SWAFFHAM, NORFOLK, ENGLAND

https://stevepdp.dev hello@stevepdp.dev

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Adept in frontend performance.
 Profiling with Dev Tools, Lighthouse and PageSpeed Insights.
- Adept in HTML, CSS and JavaScript primitives. Using design patterns and resilient CSS approaches.
- Use of CanIUse, Polyfills and BrowserStack to make the most of and test modern web features.
- Wordpress templates powered by ACF Pro and Custom Fields.
- PHP & MySQL custom applications.
 Using PHPMyAdmin, XDebug, Linux shell tools for management etc.
- SCP, SFTP and Git for deployment.
 Working within CPanel, WHM and Linux-based virtual servers.
- Docker, Vagrant and npm workflows for local devops.
- Git and GitHub workflows including repo and organisation management.
- Managing domains, associated services, CDNs and invalidating caches etc.
- On-site and remote collaboration utilising Trello, Jira, Confluence, Miro and Google Workspace tools.
- Agile sprint planning, prototyping, documenting, stand-up meetings and retrospectives.

PROFILE

With eight years of commercial web development experience. I've honed my craft at two creative agencies in West Norfolk, complemented by personal projects including recently a games portfolio in Jekyll. My journey has been fuelled by a passion for creating resilient, mobile-friendly and highly performant website experiences.

Eager to embrace new challenges among a team of progressive web folk, I'm actively pursuing a role that offers hybrid-working flexibility. My goal is to elevate the mobile website experience, deliver exceptional value to stakeholders, and thrive as I advance in my discipline. I'm ready to bring my creativity, dedication, and collaborative spirit to a team that values excellence.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Web Developer. Sidekick Digital. (2015-2021)

- Expertise in modern web standards and with a passion for delivering high quality mobile-first experiences.
- Performance profiling, analysis and advanced optimisation utilising Google Dev Tools, Lighthouse and PageSpeed Insights.
- Wordpress with ACF Pro for tailored websites and commerce.
- Shared hosting (WHM, CPanel) and VPS deployments, configurations, maintenance and migrations. DNS panels etc.
- Local dev-ops (Docker, Vagrant, npm) and documentation.
- Design sprints, agile sprint planning and retrospectives.
- Rapid prototyping of web and mobile app products.
- Quality assurance, distributed app testing and publishing.

Web Developer. Binarydrive. (2013-2015)

- PSD to HTML & CSS development and testing in BrowserStack.
- HTML email templates and legacy client testing with Litmus.
- jQuery for real-time A/B split testing of conversion funnels.
- LAMP projects utilising SFTP and/or Git for deployment.
- Time tracking and task management on an internal practice management server.

IT Manager. Overburys Solicitors. (2010-2012)

- Windows desktop deployment and general IT maintenance.
- Windows Server, Active Directory and Terminal Server services.
- PMS, digital dictation, email server/client support.
- On-site and on-call helpdesk utilising RDP and OpenVPN for direct desktop/server assistance.
- General IT hardware maintenance and installation across office sites in Norwich and Diss.

SOFT SKILLS

- A "t-shaped" frontend web developer with a wide range of skills in adjacent disciplines.
- Keeping abreast of browser developments and adapting to changing market and technology trends.
- Cultivated digital skills for focus and discipline. Striving to make the most of availableresources.
- Teamwork skills in design-thinking, strategy, and pair-programming, both in-person and distributed.
- Patient and with the ability to debate, manage conflict and find common ground among differing views.

EDUCATION

City College Norwich

Foundation Degree in Business Computing (2007-2010)

OTHER EXPERIENCE

- Eight successful years in digital agencies as a professional web developer with references.
- Personal projects including a game development portfolio and blog created with Jekyll and hosted on GitHub.
- Working at the leading edge of web standards, I'm immersed in "Indie Web" culture and passionate about the development of mobile-friendly experiences.
- Continual skills development via structured digital books and courseware from respected industry leads and developer relations figureheads.

PROJECTS

Games By Stephen Pearce (Jekyll, 2024)

My game development portfolio website. It was created with Jekyll for static rendering, version controlled with Git and is hosted upon GitHub pages via Cloudflare for wide availability and caching among other things.

Now on it's third iteration, the website uses Jekyll's Minima theme for it's proven reliable foundations. As such, it is a stack that'll last and I get complex features for free such as a complete and standards-compliant RSS feed.

Among many Liquid template customisations, I also provide a custom stevepdp.css stylesheet which overrides Minima's defaults, adding my own branding as well as dark mode support. The website is mobile friendly and scores highly across Google Lighthouse and PageSpeed Insights. SEO and social media tags have also been optimised utilising Jekyll's SEO plugin as well as my own deliberately crafted HTML document outline and page title preferences.

Perhaps the most complicated part of this project was getting the date ordinals to render correctly on blog post summaries and pages. The "st", "nd", "rd" components of date readouts. For these, I utilised ChatGPT to reason about the problem and generate the relevant parts of the Liquid template code, refactoring parts to improve and make it my own.

Hosted: https://stevepdp.dev

• Source: https://github.com/stevepdp.github.io

REFERENCES

Available upon request.